<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>

  <element name="Feats" type="Option" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_OPTION_ALLOW_FEATS">
    <description>
      <p>A feat represents a talent or an area of expertise that gives a character special capabilities. It embodies training, experience, and abilities beyond what a class provides.</p>
      <p class="indent">At certain levels, your class gives you the Ability Score Improvement feature. Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking that feature to take a feat of your choice instead. You can take each feat only once, unless the feat’s description says otherwise.</p>
      <p class="indent">You must meet any prerequisite specified in a feat to take that feat. If you ever lose a feat’s prerequisite, you can’t use that feat until you regain the prerequisite. For example, the Grappler feat requires you to have a Strength of 13 or higher. If your Strength is reduced below 13 somehow—perhaps by a withering curse— you can’t benefit from the Grappler feat until your Strength is restored.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="default">true</set>
      <set name="short">Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking the Ability Score Improvement feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking the Ability Score Improvement feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Average Hit Points" type="Option" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_OPTION_ALLOW_AVERAGE_HP">
    <description>
      <p>The character is awarded the average amount of hit points based on their hit dice.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="default">false</set>
      <set name="short">The character is awarded the average amount of hit points based on their hit dice.</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>The character is awarded the average amount of hit points based on their hit dice instead of random rolled (or manually edited) hit points.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Customized Language" type="Option" source="Internal" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE">
    <description>
      <p>You can replace one language granted by your race with any other standard language of your choice.</p>
      <p class="indent">This optional rule is drawn from Tasha's Cauldron of Everything (Customizing Your Origin).</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="default">true</set>
      <set name="short">Replace your racial language with any standard language of your choice.</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>Your racial language is replaced with a standard language of your choice.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Customized Proficiencies" type="Option" source="Internal" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY">
    <description>
      <p>If your race grants you proficiency in a skill, you can replace that proficiency with proficiency in another skill of your choice.</p>
      <p class="indent">This optional rule is drawn from Tasha's Cauldron of Everything (Customizing Your Origin).</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="default">true</set>
      <set name="short">Replace a racial skill proficiency with any other skill proficiency of your choice.</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>Your racial skill proficiency is replaced with a skill proficiency of your choice.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Customized Ability Score Increases" type="Option" source="Internal" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI">
    <description>
      <p>If you'd like your character to follow their own path, you may move the ability score increases that come with your race to different ability scores. The increases must still be divided in the same way as the original trait — if your race normally grants a +2 and a +1, you still choose one ability for the +2 and a different ability for the +1.</p>
      <p class="indent">This optional rule is drawn from Tasha's Cauldron of Everything (Customizing Your Origin).</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="default">true</set>
      <set name="short">Move racial ability score increases to ability scores of your choice (+2 to one, +1 to a different one).</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>Your racial ability score increases are applied to ability scores of your choice.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!--<element name="DEBUG OPTION" type="Option" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_OPTION_DEBUG_OPTION">
    <description>
      <p>Debugging</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="default">false</set>
      <set name="short">Debugging</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>Debugging</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Companion Ability Score Improvement" supports="Ability Score Improvement, Companion" number="2" />
    </rules>
  </element>-->
</elements>
